JANE LOW SHU PING

PHONE: 82234320 E-MAIL: JANELOW@LIVE.COM

Professional Summary

With 6 years of working experience in the Asset Management Industry, I have a good understanding of middle to back functions within the industry. I am currently handling trade matching and settlements which involves products such as Equities, Bonds, FX and Fixed Deposits. Account Openings are also within my job scope. Prior to my current role, I was in a Client Servicing role as well as Client Reporting role in a Global Custodian Bank for close to 2 years, which enabled me to obtain comprehensive knowledge of the global custody sphere. I possess a client-orientated mindset and the independence and dynamism necessary to provide quality work and efficiency to complete tasks ahead of time. I am self motivated and a fast learner.

Experience

Middle Office – Trade Processing Team Amundi Singapore Limited

MAY 2016 TO CURRENT

- Comprehensive understanding of workflow of Equities, Fixed Income and FX products
- Worked along-side team leader on a major migration project of the Middle Office team from Hong Kong to Singapore. Updated static data in various platforms, did up multiple spreadsheets which were necessary for day-to-day operations and provided multiple suggestions on process improvements to enable the team to streamline operations
- Daily exception handling on trade matching via Omgeo CTM and managed trade settlement issues
- Updating and maintenance of static data (settlement instructions) on Omgeo ALERT
- Handled derivatives such as TBA and worked alongside team-mate to automate the matching process
- Managed new account opening requests for mandates/funds for various markets
- Handled new broker account opening requests for investment of FX, Equities and Bonds
- Account mapping and trade matching via FXALL
- Handled daily fixed deposit transactions and ensured funds are remitted timely
- Ensured timeliness and accuracy in daily end-of-day trade files to end-clients
- Performed monthly reconciliation for CSA and GST reporting. Worked alongside team-mate to successfully automate these reconciliation processes
- Handled the extraction and collation of data for various regulatory reporting
- Attended and provided feedbacks to various brokers during service review meetings
- Responsive to client enquiries and able to provide resolution of issues

Senior Associate - Client Reporting Team State Street Bank and Trust (Singapore)

AUG 2015 TO MAY 2016

- Responsible for preparing and reviewing client reports which includes daily, weekly and monthly valuation reports, agreed client specific customized reports, and other ad-hoc reporting requests
- Ensured close to 100% timely and accurate delivery of reports to clients
- Point of contact for any support and enquiries relating to reporting deliverables and reconciliations
- Participated in weekly client updates, monthly client service reviews with clients and internal teams
- Oversight to internal reconciliation team and review the daily cash and stock reconciliation ledgers
- Involved in a project involving the transition/ outsourcing of reporting function
- Handled the system aspect of all account openings and terminations
- Reviewed team's procedures

Associate - Client Service State Street Bank and Trust (Singapore)

AUG 2014 TO AUG 2015

- Act as the primary point of contact for leading investment manager clients for assigned work streams such as Transaction Management, Reconciliations, Corporate Actions, Record Keeping and Data Management
- Ensured superior client experience through high quality interactions managed in an accurate, consistent and efficient manner and eased all clients' concerns
- Handled global custody queries
- Prepared scorecards, meeting agenda and minutes and participated in monthly client service reviews
- Close coordination with global colleagues is imperative to ensure that a standard operating model and strategic development approach is followed
- Monitored overdrafts and ensure that overdraft compensation is collected timely, overdraft cause is accurately communicated, while escalating potential issues to management
- Ensured all reporting deliverables are sent timely
- Did up procedures on daily tasks and perform other duties as required

Senior Officer (Cash team) UOB Asset Management Operations

APRIL 2012 to JULY 2014

- In charge of client's account opening/ closure of investment portfolios with UOBAM
- Reviewed documents including investment agreements and account opening documents
- Handled FX account opening and Fixed Deposit account opening
- Processing of FX Forwards and Fixed Deposit transactions and ensure accuracy, timeliness and swift settlement. Confirmed with brokers on the FX netting amounts before settlement date.
- Good knowledge on SWIFT messages (MT199, MT103, MT202, MT210)
- Handled all cash-related queries and issues and ensured resolution
- Good knowledge on valuation reports and ensured accuracy of all client's reports
- Reviewed and submitted regulatory requirements such as the quarterly Department of Statistic reporting and yearly MAS Survey on behalf of the department
- Worked alongside team lead to do up process maps and guided new team members

Senior Officer (Trade Settlement Team) UOB Asset Management Operations

JULY 2011 to APRIL 2012

- Handled the settlement of daily trades for bonds and equities
- Daily liaison with central dealers, external counterparties and custodians/ trustees to resolve all trade related issues
- Usage of SWIFT messages on a daily basis (i.e. MT54x, MT210, MT202, MT599)
- Managed the account opening of broker accounts for various markets
- Ensured all daily trade files are sent timely to end-clients
- Able to handle high volume and meet deadlines

Education

National University of Singapore

GRADUATED JULY 2011

• Graduated with a Bachelor of Arts (MERIT) in Economics

Referee

- Winston Thng, COO, Amundi Singapore Ltd
- Chew Soo Ee, FVP, UOB Asset Management